April 4th 2022, and we have the invocation by Mrs. Rice from the first and last year, first and last year.
Or Robert Wright.
I thank you for this day, and I thank you for this room full people.
I thank the concerns that we have for the city and the direction that we wanted to go.
I ask that you bless the decisions made in the night.
I ask that you bless everybody involved.
Thank you, God, hear some.
It's in his name, I pray.
Amen.
I'd like to leave this two to the five of the United States of America.
And to the Republic for which this hands.
One nation under your eyes.
Individual with liberty and justice are all.
Thank you, Robert.
Number four of the Republic and put around scheduled personal experiences.
Five, consider gender.
Staff are currently approved out of six and seven.
Let's go move.
Second.
Simple.
Hi.
Is that?
Davis.
Hi.
Parker.
I'm Steve.
Eight.
Benjamin.
22-20.
MSUA administrative services.
емон.
Buzzy.
PCA.
That's the topic of the budget.
We didn't realize that GRGA would begin.
Charging.
Virginia's largest cost adjustment.
That began in 2021.
We also have the chartered customers that the PCA.
From passing that on, we'll also accomplish a pay for the additional energy that we're
having to pay GRDA.
So we're asking if we can recognize the revenue received from the PCA, not so long periods
are expenditures, be able to pay for power cost adjustment today.
We just want to cost this this year to keep the power of the water.
This is different than the storm.
It's different than the PCA actually.
Just in our monthly bills, they're more than what we budgeted because of the PCA.
Therefore, we did not budget enough to share the cover of that.
So by the extra revenues coming in, we're able to cover the rest of the bills for the rest of the year.
Yeah, I'm quite sure for Mike, just a non-foreseen
thing that.
Yes sir.
It's a significant amount of the misbye.
In the greenhouse years, I've been here this is the first time we've been charged here.
So what was it?
Did you increase many drugs?
Yes sir.
I mean, three to more.
Yes.
So our contract of GRDA obviously allows them to have
a big pop, they passed through this nature for power cost adjustment.
They feel the need to pass certain costs through.
They do have that ability and we're willing to do so.
So this is always something that's been out there.
I know it's been done in the past.
You know, we sit out there's a possibility.
So whenever they've built it, didn't we have to pay it?
But it is completely separate from the PCAX charge.
We'll be talking about later for the store here.
So is anybody known when the last time is that?
So they get done?
Do you know what I mean?
We've got four years of them?
Yeah.
Since they've done so.
When they just do it, and they don't say, here's why.
What do you get to think?
So it's the first required business.
So natural gas.
You know, it's a capacity increase.
So they're passing that cost on.
If my car was working here, what does this turn is like,
two times with a feeling to the customer.
This has been been built just to live last year.
So if I'm using this to the past.
It's going to vary for every household based on the uses of that.
Some of these.
Some of the dollar.
I mean, low dollars.
Two or three or four dollars.
Maybe a bill.
And how long is it going to go back?
There's some.
We can't really ask questions.
There's me.
So if you hang around afterwards, we'll get your answers.
Last meeting was a little different.
It's so.
But this one we're going to have to get to stay on schedule.
And we'll ask him questions.
And we'll try to ask him the ones you want.
But if we don't, then feel free to hang around afterwards.
We'll make sure you get them answered.
Okay.
Thank you.
So when they charge us an overage like this.
That's pretty much forever right there, I never go down.
I mean, this is again, this is something that they have the ability to charge us.
I mean, we have to recover it to pay them.
But again, like Mike said, we've been, they've been doing this since July, I'm last year.
I think it actually started in June and in the years of the patient of the July.
We had an estimate ever month, but at the month or four,
I don't know what they're going to charge us, so we can start charging it at the beginning of the month.
So we're prepared to pay it at the end of the month.
Again, it just comes with a bad time.
With us talking about the storm charges.
Probably wouldn't have been noticed before, but it kind of seems like it's going to conjunction.
I think it's you mentioned in the price of natural gas.
It used to be these to be negative.
So that's what people that notice is on the bill.
And then you know, natural gas.
And it's all fuel, all their fuel costs cold, and everything.
So you know, they're pretty mad into that person power cost.
They're going to actually pass it on to us.
There's other communities that they started to get the same.
Yes.
And then that is on your bill.
So we're not, this is a constituting of change.
That what Mike's talking about here is not constantly changing.
Like he said, this is a part of me since last year.
But this is just a budget amendment for us to do it on the back side of the budget.
We've been having to pay work on our GRA bills.
And what we would have originally budgeted since we didn't know they were going to charge the PCA.
So now we're getting later into the fiscal year.
And we need to make sure that we have enough in that con to cover those expenses prior to the remaining of the fiscal time.
It's already being done.
We're just clear to the end of the action.
Right.
We have the ordinance.
We want to start in a set has been set for years.
And we have the judging that we have.
We're just trying to balance out the extent.
Motion to approve.
Say.
Davis.
Parker.
Michael.
Hi.
He's said.
I've heard.
Thank you.
Nine.
Notting a rate adjustment for electric sales.
Providing.
Providing for the creation of the temporary rate adjustment.
For the winter storm, you're a temporary production cost.
Bill recovery and providing an effective date.
Right.
We've already went through this power points.
You know.
And that's being made a couple changes.
It's a better.
It's straight to date.
That it's dark.
And we previously had some questions.
So.
Being able to discuss those.
And let's go ahead and go through.
Just for anyone that's watching online.
Anything or the audience tonight.
It's not fully aware of what we talked about.
You can walk through it.
Then I'll have a time.
Okay.
Okay, so we have February 2021, we had Winner Stormy Erie during Winner Storm, Erie Agierie,
and got a one hundred and two million dollars bill for their natural gas that they use at one of their
planets. We did not provide natural gas, but if you notice on your gas bill that you got from
a ONG, or can it's not for gas that even when I have a should have got something in your mail,
I don't know about it going up. So, I can talk about, you know, the price of the natural gas went
from $2.95 to $1.00 to $1.00 to $1.00 first trip, six straight day, so obviously it was a large
increase minus portion of that was $2.698, $4.59, so $2.7 million. And then minus often to pay this amount by
October 31st, 2022. On your bill, this ordinance will create a PCA X rider on your bill, so you'll notice
it will just say PCA X and then amount, and then we took Jill and her staff put together the
use of just for the past three years, and she shows, based on PCA X number at that point,
zero zero five to two seven. This would be our, say the amount that's up here to collect,
and then every returners are industrial customers, they will, there are going to be billed from their
actual usage, turning them up. So, anything in my dust for customer and anything in my jayna farms,
sector, options, the college, the marine, the flow run, the flow run, thank you, the hospital,
the stables, the stables was one of them on it, no, I don't think so. I'm sorry if I didn't remember
the extent of the cold weather. So, you know, because of the over majority of the country,
and this is the area that SBB, so in the southwest park, which Jerry, as I remember,
did dates, so you never remember, we had that Sunday, whenever we started to roll it to,
I declared EA level one, and Monday was whenever we started conserving power, and then when we had our first
rollings back up, I mean, 10 days, and for on Tuesday, it was when we did our second one,
which was a little more controlled, EA got better from there, because we only got to EA level two,
on Wednesday, from there on. So, the drivers of the temporary service interruption,
I can still supply, they talk about ice and extreme cold weather,
they're really downages,
transmission congestion and then the tight end of the supply,
neighboring areas.
This shows the level of generation.
And some of the people don't think about it is,
you do not want these plants to get down,
because if you get these plants down,
then you have to bring them back up slowly.
You can just turn a switch in there.
We drop our whole city of Malmolo,
on their power plant, and we make it go down.
So I mean, if it would ever go down,
then you have to bring them up slowly.
And then they would say, hey, can you bring this in any way?
What's on why?
Can you bring this in any more army?
That's something you definitely don't know.
You have to take two or three days.
So this is that, that's a lot of the natural gas prices from Henry Head.
So you can see we're going on, I think, $2, $2, $2, $3.
And then BitBoy is our team that's five to two, $400.
And then you can see we're going to over $1,000.
Part of that concern.
And now, our energy prices, they talked about,
and this is just kind of talking about the generation.
Even shows February 21, February 20, 2020.
So Jerry had a lot of their coal going pretty much everybody.
And that's BBL, our coal going, because that's what they can get enough gas.
This was, you know, the question was asked,
what is there in the country that you use it?
So you know, residential customer, you around that $900,
and then you a general commercial industrial, industrial,
industrial, this kind of shows the different breakdown.
When you got asked, who would be, I could get a commercial account.
So that would be like a gas station, you know, kind of the large user,
but not a industrial level user.
And I want to do the calculations.
So you take the, you know, if you want to know your bill,
you even take your KWH usage, times the PCAX number.
So the 0.00 or 526, times your usage.
It would just kind of went through some different examples.
So the amount of the KWH usage, times that, you know,
if you have to put a $5 or $5 bill, you know,
the commercial account that average is about $80.00.
So I'm interested to see, like, how the first six months is going to go,
just to see if we will continue to, if you will continue to say,
you used to work to be a decrease possibility, because you have to
block our business and other PCAX that's going to be on their bill.
So it may fluctuate our numbers a little bit, be interesting.
But I'm happy to help anybody, you know, calculate their bill.
You just take your usage, times that number.
You know, there's some such immediate questions.
If you have to go on 100,000 KWH, so if you pay the PCAX,
or if you have to do, what does it bring down on it?
understand. So, you know, this is what the industrial customers were paying. This is what other
regulations are paying. And this is actually a snippet from our bill from GERDIATION on the
week of the 269-459. So, the question was, how's the energy of the public utility of the
department already paid this bill GERDIATION? No, we have not. Well, the PCX chart, if we were to
even once it's paid back, and so, yes, it will be removed. Well, the customer has had to pay
the PCX even though they have started to share the time, and as he has moved money until they
have spent the interest charge on any of this now that will not. The GERDIATION is kind of a breakdown.
We've talked about from the last week on our bill, we've made this up together kind of the pricing
structure. It is hard to compare utilities just because they're so many different factors that they
have went into it. So, I mean, my gift friend, my double head in Talukwalk, you know, you know, you've built
this 54 dollars and 63 cents, but I don't know, because I always bring this up, but his transfer was
750,000 a year, which is obviously, that's a way less than the city of Lima's utility transfer, which
is a general fund. So, you know, if we transferred that, well, I'm not going to be going to probably come
up closer to this rate, but when we transfer money, you know, it does go to streets, it does go to parks,
it does go to the blue sunfire. So, there is a situation in the prior, but the same way, you know,
they have utility boards as totally separate than the city. So, there are rates, obviously,
we reflect that. Here's just about kind of the way it would show up in order. And then this was how
we compare you in northeast, this would be northeast, this would mean city, and this would be an M.R.
other good deal. It was kind of show in you. Any question? I think I see that hard one honestly, but
it never got good. You did good. So, I didn't have a question from some, from a member of the community,
I don't know if J.R.A. had some type of fund, like emergency fund, or something like that,
but it set up for things like this. To have a rate stabilization fund, we've asked them to use that on
their petition, and I'm interested in wanting to use it towards this. How much is in there, you know?
It would only be, I guess, at this point, because that would be a big given us a solid number.
But what we got was a number that was much lower than what we had heard so
I think there was some confusion in the translation of what we were asking for, so I think
what we had in the time.
I knew that was their response was around $30 million, but a $30 million rate
stabilization fund for the organization of that size wouldn't make it safe.
The last time they published their financial statement, which was, I believe, in 2019, which
would have been for the year of 2018, they put $20 million into that fund that year.
But it never gave what the balance of it was.
That's kind of a head scratcher that they would use that to help out their customers, huh?
What do we can do with your other head scratchers like that?
Okay, now came out of here and covered their customers' bills in the area of Canada.
I won't be able to define some of their bonds because we can't control G or G or G.
I'd love to have to see it on their board, but we don't have to see it on their board.
Why is that?
There's pressure.
Come on, let's go out.
Can we have that to break down here and answer for this?
All right, so, you know, the question for Tyler?
So if I could explain the modifications of the ordinance from what you got in your original packet,
that, that was an ordinance that was drafted by Ken and Tyler.
I didn't actually see it until today, but the last time we had a rate adjustment, if you'll recall,
Josh Fleming was in raising a question about the actual timing of how that rate went into effect.
And so, as an effort to clear it up, because this ordinance does not have an emergency clause on it,
it doesn't go into effect for 30 days, so that would take us to May the 4th.
The new rate will start applying to all billing cycles that begin after that.
And so that means it will actually be reflected in the bills that go out in the month of June.
The other change that I have made here, well, a couple of other changes.
One is that it said that it would, the new rate would end at the end of 36 months.
But if, for some reason, our utility usage were to go down significantly.
At the end of 36 months, it may not cover the total amount that we're owe it.
So I removed that part and just said it remains in effect until we have raised that
exact amount that we're paying to GRDA.
Then the other two changes, section three, is that this is not codified, in other words, it
doesn't go into the big fact book, simply because it is a temporary ordinance, and then
thirdly, it just makes it real clear that the affected data this is 30 days from today.
Hey Tyler, what's the current rate that we're paying for kilowatt hour right now?
From GRDA?
Well, we're getting charged on our fields.
I'd actually look at it because it fluctuates a month later.
But I guess people are not understanding that this is not a rate increase.
This is just a line I didn't be input on there, but everything has put out online,
what Ben just said is that it's a temporary rate increase.
I mean, it's really misleading to the customers of what it really is.
Okay, it's an expensive cover.
So the wording's wrong, like it's being portrayed wrong.
I've had a lot of people call me and ask me about it, and it's not a rate increase.
It's just like he said, it's a recovery.
So we need to make it clear, we pay this or this in between here for a kilowatt hours.
And we need to make sure that everybody knows that's not going to change.
So technically, and you are absolutely correct there,
technically in the ordinance where we're identifying it as a temporary rate adjustment
to cover that cost of what they're passing on to us.
But yes, I agree with what you're saying.
But whatever you call it, it doesn't taste good.
Right, it's designed to recover a specific set of what's that a manager recovery goes away.
And that's quite a not adjusting what we're currently paying, no honor to get a lot of that.
That would stay the same as it was set in order to buy the council back in the 1617.
Whatever that was last 18, that will state effect and utility such time that there is another
rate study brought me.
And if there's a change in that, whether it be lower or higher, the council would have to improve that at that time.
It would be set at that time and state effect.
you need to, yeah, you need action to approve this, but we will actually approve the ordinance itself in the council meeting.
We've always approved them below and then it's you and, right.
I think it needs to be clearly stated that it's just the recovery that everybody needs understand it's not raised in our costs.
So, are you on board with just what changed the recovery?
Well, if you all want that, we can do that.
I think if you read the title of the ordinance and in the exhibit, it clearly talks about it as a temporary rate adjustments.
I just know we need to be clear to our citizens and what it actually is because there may not be.
Can we modify that word, make the recovery?
We still have a judgment.
I'm going to prove that pending that change.
We can, but I personally think that the word adjustment would be the better term.
We already have bill recovery, and that's what I mean, wouldn't it stay the same?
I'll leave the adjustment just down here we've got bill recovery, couldn't I mean.
We could change the word rate.
The creation of a temporary rate recovery adjustment.
Can we just take a rate out?
Right out.
Just say a temporary adjustment.
If we did that though, I mean, I can go over to the office and make those changes, but if you take the word rate out,
then that would mean a lot more.
changes to the wording throughout the whole ordinance.
Gotcha.
In and of itself the word grade is not important because it's fixed.
Right.
Yes.
That is great.
Why don't we, you all decide on the exact wording that you want and then we can approve it with
that wording to be put in place.
I'd really suggest that we need to approve it today or we're going to be putting it off
further and understand from jail that that's about $50,000 every month we put it off.
So is it just a temporary cost for that word?
Well, if you dropped the word grade, it says temporary adjustment for winter storm.
Yeah.
We could do that.
And it's just, it's a fixed rating against the kilowatt hour, right?
So.
Oh, I'm good with the dollar.
I want to make sure that everybody's clear as far as our citizens are paying the back.
Well, we're actually doing here.
Is that clear from your perspective?
That's what we call it.
I was trying to understand what still what I call theirs.
I was just saying I know they recently passed it.
Well, they call it.
I don't know.
I was trying to find a second.
I think it would be read under your source and I thought that's what I did do.
They're looking on Facebook.
They're just, we can't change them.
I'm absolutely it's a rate factor.
It is a rate factor.
Right.
But it's a temporary adjustment.
So.
I mean, we know what it is.
Right.
We know what's happening.
We're not everybody.
Correct.
I agree with you.
So if you want to just take that word rate out.
I think that rate.
I just think the word has a negative connotation to the public whenever you talk about our rates.
What's my rates on my bill?
That seems like a, like Duane said that's a generalization of what's happening and not actually a real story.
And our society, we hardly ever get a chance to talk about that word in terms of a decrease.
Right.
So it does come off negative whether we like it or not.
So that change would be in the title.
The word is used in the last where as I'm very drawn.
But I don't think it is.
I think it is appropriate there.
But then we would take it out of section one.
Why?
one, section two, line one, and then in the billing table in the background, it would come
out from there, and then we would change the abbreviation TRA to TA.
I'm going to go with that. So we've approved with many of those changes?
Yes, and authorize you to sign it once those changes are needed.
Let's take a look at this.
All right.
Submer.
Double.
Hi.
Estep.
Perfect.
Hi.
J.M.
Any new business or business, of course, you have this agenda.
I live in trustee community announcements.
We're at all the Germans.
Somebody.
Excuse me.
Estep.
Hi.